thomascookairlines.com 2019-05-20

# Privacy & Cookies Policy - Thomas Cook Airlines

Our Company

Current:  Privacy & Cookies Policy 

## Privacy Policy and Information on Cookies

Thomas Cook Airlines understands and respects the importance of protecting your personal data. This Privacy Policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us, in respect of your relationship with us as a customer or a potential customer in respect of our flight seat sales and other related services.

This information can be collected via our website, Thomas Cook Airlines, (“Site”), our call centres, our retail stores, our mobile applications (“Apps”), our questionnaires/surveys, or our social media channels (collectively, our “Services”). 

Please read the following information carefully. You are responsible for ensuring that the other people that you are acting on behalf of (such as those included with you on a booking), are aware of the content of this Privacy Policy and you have checked with them that they agree to their personal data being given to us to make a booking or other purchase on their behalf.

By making a booking or other purchase or otherwise giving your personal data to us, we will transfer, store or process it as set out below. We will take all reasonably necessary steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

 **Thomas Cook Airlines is registered in the UK and is part of the Thomas Cook Group Airlines and the wider Thomas Cook Group that includes  ** **a number of companies registered within the UK and overseas.  ** **This policy covers the Thomas Cook Airlines business.  **

 **Important:** when you make a flight booking via this website, your payment will be processed by Thomas Cook Airlines Limited, but your contract will be with either Thomas Cook Airlines Limited or with our affiliated company, Thomas Cook Tour Operations Limited. This is because our website provides you with the opportunity to book your flights with Thomas Cook Airlines Limited, but also provides options to book with third party airlines, such as Condor Flugdienst GmbH, Thomas Cook Airlines Scandinavia A/S and Thomas Cook Airlines Balearics S.L.U. 

When we say ‘we’ or ‘us’ in this Policy, we’re generally referring to the separate and distinct companies that make up Thomas Cook Group’s airline businesses. Therefore:

  * if your booking only consists of flights operated by Thomas Cook Airlines Limited, your contract will be with Thomas Cook Airlines Limited; and 
  * if your booking includes a flight with a third party airline your contract will be with Thomas Cook Tour Operations Limited. 

This Policy applies to personal data processed by the following companies, including data collected when you make bookings, purchases and enquiries with them:

  *  **Thomas Cook Airlines Limited** – who are responsible for the operation of the Thomas Cook Airlines App, the Site, including managing your interaction with the Site through the ‘My Account’ area and who manage the airline telephone contact centres. 
  *  **Thomas Cook Airlines Scandanavia A/S trading as Airshoppen** – a Danish subsidiary company within the Thomas Cook Group and are responsible for operating our online duty free shop ‘Airshoppen’.
  *  **Condor Flugdienst GmbH** \- a German subsidiary company within the Thomas Cook Group who are responsible for the operation of some flights sold through the Site and through the website [www.condor.com](http://www.condor.com/ "Opens external link in new window") on behalf of Thomas Cook Airlines.  

Whenever dealing with any of the Thomas Cook Group companies, the relevant company you correspond with or make your booking with will be the data controller in relation to the processing activities described below. A “data controller” is an organisation that decides why and how your personal information is processed.

 **Please note:** except for the web pages available at [www.thomascookairlines.com]( "Opens external link in new window"), all other parts of the websites operated by the Thomas Cook Group companies, including Thomas Cook Tour Operations Limited and Thomas Cook Money Ltd will be handled and used in ways mentioned in their privacy policies (not ours). You can view those policies here: [thomascookairlines.com]( "Opens external link in new window"), [thomascookmoney.com](https://thomascookmoney.com/privacy-and-cookies.html "Opens external link in new window"), [thomascook.com](https://www.thomascook.com/privacy-policy/#intcmp=Footer_PrivacyPolicy "Opens external link in new window"), [airtours.co.uk](https://www.airtours.co.uk/privacy-policy/ "Opens external link in new window"), [club18-30.com](https://www.club18-30.com/privacy-policys/ "Opens external link in new window") and [thomascooksport.com](https://www.thomascooksport.com/Terms-and-Conditions/Privacy-Policy "Opens external link in new window").

Additionally, Thomas Cook Airlines Limited sometimes needs to subcontract its services to other airlines, both within the Thomas Cook Group and outside of the Group. Please note where this happens, you will be informed and we will need to pass your personal information to the relevant airline that will operate your flight to enable them to process and deliver your booking. In this situation the relevant terms and conditions and privacy policy will apply of the company providing your flight (not ours). 

 **We collect certain personal data about you and about any other person you include on your booking.  ** **The sort of personal data we collect is information that you provide to us,  ** **that we collect from you or observe about you, or that we obtain from other sources.  **

 **Personal data you give to us  
** When you make a booking or other purchase or enquiry we will ask you for your title, full name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, date of birth, confirmation as to which passenger is the main contact and personal travel preferences. We need to collect this information in order to arrange the travel and other services you are requesting.

When you request to make a booking, we will ask you for personal data such as information concerning dietary requirements, medical conditions, disabilities and special requirements. We need to collect this information so as to be able to consider your particular needs in relation to a booking and, where those needs can be met, we have to share that data with our third party suppliers and transfer it outside the European Economic Area (EEA), as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not want to provide this information to us, or after you have provided us with this information you ask us or our data compliance department to stop processing this information, it will mean we won’t be able to provide all or parts of the services you have requested. If we need to cancel your booking/purchase as a result, you are likely to incur a cancellation charge. Advanced notice of any relevant charges and our intention to cancel your booking/ purchase will be given to enable you to make a decision on how to proceed.

When you book a flight via the Site, we will collect Advanced Passenger Information (“API”) which includes the following information for you and any other party in your booking: full name (as it appears on your passport), date of birth, gender, nationality, passport number and expiry and country of issue, and country of residence. This information is required in advance of flight departure to and from certain destinations, a full list can be found on our Flight Preparation webpage.

* * *

For flights to and from destinations which do not require API, this information assists us to streamline our check in process and could reduce queuing time at the airport. It also ensures we fulfil our legal requirements to share personal data with relevant customs and immigration authorities (“Relevant Authorities”). 

When you make a purchase from our online duty free shop, Airshoppen, we will ask you for your title, full name, payment card details, booking information and email address. We need this information in order to process the sale for you.

If you enter a competition or promotion, complete a survey, or if you report a problem with any of our Services, we will collect your name and relevant contact information and any other personal information you choose to give us.

If you contact us online, we will keep a record of your e-mail or other correspondence, and if you call us by telephone, we will monitor and/or record phone conversations for training and customer service reasons.

If, when using our Services, or making a search on our website  you enter or provide any of your personal data (including telephone number or e-mail address), but do not make a booking or other purchase, we will keep and use the data you’ve provided for a limited time and purpose, as mentioned below.

To help us keep your information current, accurate and complete, please ensure you tell us if anything needs to be changed.

* * *

 **Personal data we collect and/or observe about you     
**Based on how you have used our Services in the past and your activity on our website, social media channels, or with our contact centre, we collect the following personal data about you:

Details of the services we have provided to you in the past, or you have recently booked with us, including your previous travel arrangements, such as flights  and other purchases, and matters related to those arrangements, such as details of your previous requirements or complaints.

We collect details of your visits to and within our Sites and Apps (including, but not limited to, searches, traffic data, website interaction, location data) this is required for our own purposes or otherwise, and of the resources that you access. We use third party technology services, such as Google Analytics to administer these services.

We collect details of some website(s) you visited before you use a link to our Sites, pages visited in our Sites, and time spent on each page.

* * *

We collect information about your computer (or mobile device/tablet) including, where available, your IP address, operating system, device location, browser type, cookie identification numbers, for system administration purposes, marketing purposes (both our own, and third party advertisers for whom we provide advertising services) and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and any reports we share do not identify any individuals.

We use Sessioncam for analysis. Sessioncam is a product that has been developed by Sessioncam Limited and record mouse clicks and movements, and page scrolling. The information collected does not include bank details or any sensitive personal data. Information collected by Sessioncam is for our internal use only and to improve our website usability and statistical reporting. 

* * *

 **Personal data obtained from other sources     
**We might also receive your personal data from third party sources who collect information about you on our behalf. This includes:

If you book one of our flight seat sales through a third party travel agent, certain personal data (as applicable to your booking, such as your name, date of birth or any special requirements you have, 

including any API) will be passed to us to provide you with the services you have requested/booked.

If you complete any of our customer feedback questionnaires/surveys, the information you provide will be processed on our behalf and provided to us by a third party such as clicktools.

If you book one of our flights through a third party agent, certain personal data such as your name, date of birth or any special requirements.

 **Your personal data is held on a combination of our own systems and systems of the suppliers we use to provide our services.   **

When you give your personal data to us, some of the personal data you provide will need to be given to and processed and stored by relevant third parties and will also be shared with other companies within the Thomas Cook Group for the purposes of providing services to us or directly to you on our behalf, including the operation and maintenance of our Site, Apps and social media pages. These third parties can be categorised as follows:

  * our technology and data management partners who help us to administer the services we provide
  * our travel partners, such as third party airlines and airlines within the Thomas Cook Group Airlines, airports, insurance companies and ground handling agents (depending on the travel services you book), so that they can provide you with the arrangements and assistance you require.
  * our card payment facilitators, that help us process customer payments and assists us in  detecting and preventing fraudulent payments or bookings.

Some of these third parties are based outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”). Organisations that are based outside of the EEA are not subject to the same level of controls in regard to data protection as exist within the UK and the EEA. We aim only to transfer your data to third parties outside of the EEA where either:

  * your personal information will be subject to one or more appropriate safeguards set out in the law, if you’d like more information about our safeguards, please contact us. These safeguards might be the use of standard contractual clauses in a form approved by regulators, or having our suppliers sign up to an independent privacy scheme approved by regulators (like the US ‘Privacy Shield’ scheme); or
  * the transfer is necessary to enable your contract to be performed.

Due to the decision of the UK leaving the EU, the way your data is transferred from the UK to other countries may change to ensure continuing compliance with data protection regulations. This will depend on the data protection rules in placefor international transfers of data outside of the UK once the UK has left the EU. The security of your data will not change.

In order for you to travel overseas, we may be required to disclose certain of your personal data to government bodies or other authorities in the UK and in other countries, such as those responsible for immigration, border control, law enforcement, security and anti-terrorism.  Even if it is not mandatory for us to provide information to such authorities, we may exercise our discretion to assist them where appropriate in the interests of detecting and preventing criminal activity.

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our Group for business purposes including holding your data on central/ shared systems for delivering the Services to you and processing your booking. Our Group means our subsidiaries and our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries.  For example where you have booked a flight with a third party airline/carrier, your data will be passed to Thomas Cook Tour Operations Limited as the party who you are contracting and to the third party airline/carrier providing your flight (as applicable).

Thomas Cook Airlines Limited sometimes needs to subcontract its services to other airlines, some of which are within the Thomas Cook Group of Companies. In this situation it will be necessary to pass your data to the relevant airline that will operate your flight. In this situation their Terms and conditions and Privacy Policy will apply.

We may pass your data to relevant third parties, such as a payment facilitator Concardis  for the purpose of detecting and preventing fraudulent payments or bookings.

 **In order to provide our services to you, we use the information we hold in a number of different ways. We process your information either because it is necessary for us to do so as part of a contract you enter into,  ** **because we have a legitimate business reasons for doing so, or because we have a Legal Obligation to.**

We will use and process your personal information as set out below where it is necessary for us to carry out pre-contract steps you have requested, or for the performance of our contract:

  * To administer your booking internally and communicating your booking externally with our suppliers, to ensure the services you have requested are arranged;
  * To communicate with you regarding your booking or any other purchase, including sending booking confirmation and travel documents;
  * To notify you about changes to your booking to changes to the flight schedule or other services or products available through this website;
  * To fulfil our contractual obligations to you, including your flight and any other services or products you order;

* * *

  * To run our competitions and promotions that you enter from time to time and to distribute prizes;
  * To process your payment card or bank details when taking payment for your booking or when providing a refund; and
  * To provide Relevant Authorities with your Advance Passenger Information (API) prior to departure for flights to and from certain destinations outside the EEA. We will not be able to transport you to or from that destination without first providing your API to the Relevant Authorities. Some destinations will not provide you with the same level of protection of your personal information or data privacy rights but we will always transfer the minimum amount of personal data that is required in order to carry out our contract with you. 

* * *

We will use and process your personal information as set out below where it is **necessary for us to carry out activities for which it is in our legitimate interests as a business** to do so:

 **To improve customer experience:**

  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Sites, when you choose to do so.
  * To ensure that content from our Sites, Apps and booking systems is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer/device.
  * To notify you about changes to our service.

 **To protect our business against financial loss:**

  * For collection of outstanding payments before departure, we pass on the customer data to our airport agents in order to collect the payments.
  * For collection of the claim in case of outstanding claims after the flight, we will forward the booking information (i.e. the information you provided during the booking process) to our collection agencies.
  * For debt collection or credit vetting.
  * For payment card and booking verification on some of our sites to ensure only genuine customer bookings are made.
  * For preventing and detecting fraudulent or criminal activity.

 **To promote our business, improve our products and services:**

  * To send marketing correspondence about products and services similar to those you have previously bought from us. You can unsubscribe to receiving such electronic marketing information and this option will be included in every marketing message we send you.  See the section ‘When and how do we use your information for marketing’ for more information.

* * *

  * To send you service emails related to the product or service you have purchased from us, you can unsubscribe from such emails, this option will be included in each email sent to you apart from those emails containing essential operational communications.
  * To contact you if you make an enquiry with us on our website but do not complete a booking to check if there was a problem or you need any assistance to book.
  * For internal research/analysis to improve the quality of our Services, the products we offer and new products we are developing by:  
\- Inviting customers to take part in surveys or customer/business discussion groups.  
\- Using aggregated customer data to make informed decisions based on analysis of customer booking or other purchase trends and behaviours.
  * To promote our business, brands and products and measure the reach and effectiveness of our campaigns:  
\- To contact you with targeted advertising delivered online through social media and other platforms operated by other companies such as Criteo and Google. You will receive advertising based on information about you that we have provided to the platform or because, at our request, the platform has identified you as having similar attributes to the individuals whose details it has received from us. To find out more, please refer to the information provided in the help pages of the platforms on which you receive advertising from us.   
\- To obtain more information about you by sharing your personal information with technology companies or platforms who also hold information about you and can match their records with ours.  We/these companies use cookies to match the personal information each of us hold about you (see further our Cookies Policy). 

* * *

We use this information in two ways:

  * We identify links between your attributes and your behaviours and market to others with the same attributes, in our direct marketing campaigns and through targeted advertising delivered through our Sites, Apps or third party platforms including social media channels.
  * We tailor and personalise our interactions with you to make them more relevant to your interests. These interactions include your journey around our Sites and the content that appears on it and marketing communications we send or show to you in our direct marketing campaigns and through online targeted advertising described in the paragraph above. Please see ‘How we personalise marketing for you’ for more information.

 **To support any potential company sale or acquisition:**

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

We will use and process your personal information as set out below where we consider that it is in your vital interests that we do:  

  * To assist you or arrange for assistance to be provided to you by third parties either in the event of an incident or emergency.

We will use and process your personal information as set out below where we have your consent to do so:

  * To assist you or arrange for assistance to be provided to you by third parties where you have special requirements in relation to medical, health or dietary aspects of your booking.

  * To send marketing correspondence about our products and services where we have asked for your consent to do so. See the section ‘When and how do we use your information for marketing for more information’.

We and third parties acting on our instructions, such as external law firms and their employees, use and process your personal information as set out below where there is a legal requirement for us to do so:

  * To identify you when corresponding with us.
  * For resolving complaints, dealing with disputes and legal proceedings. This might include contacting you proactively if we need to resolve any issues you experience or have experienced with a booking or other purchase.
  * To keep a record relating to the exercise of any of your rights relating to our processing of your personal information.
  * To take any actions in relation to health and safety incidents required by law.
  * Processing Advanced Passenger Information (API) in advance of departure of flights to ensure that we meet our legal requirements to share your API data with Relevant Authorities, or other similar disclosures as required by law for example with the US Department for Homeland Security, pursuant to an agreement between the EU and the US, for the reasons explained in this text.

 **To find out more about our marketing communications, including when and how we may contact you and how you can opt out of marketing.**

If you have made an enquiry or purchase on one of our Sites, your personal data may be used by us in the ways the law allows, to contact you by post, electronic means (e-mail) and/or by phone with information and offers relating to products or services that you can book/purchase from Thomas Cook companies. We will only do this if you did not opt out of such marketing where we collected your contact details.

If you have not made an enquiry or purchase, we will only send you information and offers by e-mail or text message if you sign up (opt in) to receive such marketing by email, either directly through us or by telling a third party that you would like to receive marketing from us. We try to adapt any marketing material that we send to you, for example by notifying you of special offers or promotions that apply to your interests and in your location. If you do not wish to receive email communications from us, please inform us by using the unsubscribe link inside the email.

The type of products and services that can be booked/purchased through Thomas Cook are shown in the table below. You will only receive marketing communications about those which we think are relevant to you:

 **Travel and travel related services from our group companies**

  * Flight seat sale and flight ancillary services (such as in-flight meals, baggage allowance, upgraded seat options from Thomas Cook Airlines Limited.

  * ‘Airshoppen’ online duty free shop from Thomas Cook Airlines Scandinavia A/S trading as Airshoppen.
  * Insurance provided by White Horse Insurance Ireland.
  * Foreign Exchange provided by Thomas Cook Money Limited.

 **For financial products/services from Thomas Cook Money Ltd**

  * Foreign Exchange (Reserve and Collect & Home Delivery) supplied by TCCT Retail Ltd

 **Third party products / services which you can book through us**

  * Car Hire
  * Transfers
  * Holiday Extras (for airport parking and hotels and car hire)

We will **not** pass your contact details to a third party that is not one of our business partners involved in providing Thomas Cook services or products for them to contact you or send you marketing communications unless you have expressly agreed that we can do so. 

 **To try and ensure that our marketing communications and advertising are relevant to you,  ** **we work with third parties to offer a better experience to customers and potential customers.**

Using new technologies and with the help of our advertising agencies and marketing activation platforms including Yieldify, Criteo, and Google  may, we will use your personal information in the following ways:

  * to try to ensure any marketing communications we send to you are offering products or services likely to be of interest to you.
  * to tailor and track our digital marketing (for example, our internet banner advertisements) and links from our marketing partners' websites to our Sites. This digital marketing will include marketing related to Thomas Cook or marketing related to third parties to whom we provide advertising services.

Our business partners and advertising networks  will also serve you with adverts on our Sites.  We allow third parties to collect information about your online activities using cookies and other technologies.

The third parties may include other Thomas Cook companies, our suppliers/business partners who collect information when you view or interact with an advert on one of our Sites, and advertising networks. We also collect information about your online activities using cookies and other technologies when you use websites other than our Sites to provide advertising services to third parties. This technology allows us to display an advert to you relating to a third party on other websites based on your page visits and other behaviours whilst on our Sites.

The information collected by these third parties might be used to make predictions about your preferences or interests and to display adverts on our Sites or across the internet appropriate to those perceived interests.  Please see our Cookies Policy for more information.

 **We understand you might no longer want to hear from us and that’s ok.   It is easy to opt-out or unsubscribe.**

You have the right at any time to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by selecting the ‘no marketing’ option on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise this right at any later time by using the unsubscribe link on any marketing e-mail you receive, by following the opt-out instructions on any direct marketing communication sent to you or by sending an unsubscribe request to: Database Manager, Marketing, Thomas Cook Airlines, Hangar 1, Western Maintenance Area, Runger Lane, Manchester Airport, Manchester, M90 5FL. Or by way of email to [unsubscribe-pbas@thomascookairlines.com](mailto:unsubscribe-pbas@thomascookairlines.com "Opens window for sending email").  

 **Please note** – when you unsubscribe from marketing in respect of a flight seat sale or related   travel services, this opt-out will apply only to the Thomas Cook company making the marketing communication.  If you receive marketing directly from Airshoppen  and if you wish to opt-out from their direct marketing you will need to follow the instructions on their website or follow unsubscribe notices in their marketing communications. 

 **You have a number of rights in relation to your personal information under data protection law.**

 **Your Right to Access Your Personal Information  
** You have the right to make a Data Subject Access Request in many circumstances.  That is a request for access to the personal information that we hold about you.  If we agree that we have to provide personal information to you (or someone else on your behalf), we’ll provide it to you or them free of charge in most circumstances.

We will ask for proof of identity and sufficient information about your interactions with us that we can locate your personal information. That will include information about your previous booking(s) or other purchases. If someone is acting on your behalf they will need to provide written and signed confirmation from you that you have given your authority to that person/company for them to make the request. 

* * *

We will ask for this to be provided before we give you (or another person acting on your behalf) a copy of any of your personal information we hold. We will not provide you with a copy of your personal information if it includes the personal information of other individuals or we have another lawful reason to withhold that information.

Please see the section titled ‘How to Contact Us’ if you need to make a Data Subject Access Request.

* * *

 **Correcting and updating your personal information  
** The accuracy of your information is important to us and we are working on ways to make it easier for you to review and correct the information that we hold about you. 

* * *

In the meantime, if you change your name or address/e-mail address, or you discover that any of the other information we hold is inaccurate or out of date, please let us know by contacting our customer service team by contacting us here.

* * *

 **Withdrawing your consent  
** Where we rely on your consent as the legal basis for processing your personal information, as set out in section above titled **‘How do we use your information when providing our services to you’** , you can withdraw your consent at any time.

If you would like to withdraw your consent to receiving any direct marketing to which you previously opted-in, please see the section titled **'What you need to do if you don’t want our marketing communications’**  for further details. If you would like to withdraw your consent to us processing any special categories of personal data such as information concerning dietary requirements, medical conditions, disabilities and special requirements, please contact our customer service team here or your local store.

* * *

Please note if you ask us to stop processing this information, it can mean we won’t be able to provide all or parts of the services you have requested. If we have to cancel your booking or other purchase as a result, you are likely to incur a cancellation charge.

If you withdraw your consent, our use of your personal information before you withdraw is still lawful.

* * *

 **Objecting to our use of your personal information**    
Where we rely on our legitimate business interests as the legal basis for processing your personal information for any purpose(s), you can object to us using your personal information for these purposes by e-mailing or writing to us at the address provided at the end of this policy. Except for the purposes for which we are sure we can continue to process your personal information, we will temporarily stop processing your personal information in line with your objection until we have investigated the matter. 

* * *

If we agree that your objection is justified in accordance with your rights under data protection law, we will permanently stop using your data for those purposes. Otherwise we will provide you with our justification as to why we need to continue using your data. 

* * *

 **Erasing your personal information or restricting its processing**  
In certain circumstances, you can ask for your personal information to be removed from our systems by e-mailing or writing to us at the address at the end of this policy. Provided we do not have any continuing lawful reason to continue processing or holding your personal information, we will make reasonable efforts to comply with your request.

You can also ask us to restrict processing your personal information where you believe it is unlawful for us to do so, you have objected to its use and our investigation is pending or you require us to keep it in connection with legal proceedings.  

* * *

We will only process your personal information whilst its processing is restricted if we have your consent or are legally permitted to do so, for example for storage purposes, to protect the rights of another individual or company or in connection with legal proceedings.  

* * *

 **Transferring your personal information in a structured data file  
** Where we rely on your consent as the legal basis for processing your personal information or need to process it in connection with your contract, as set out in section titled **‘How do we use your information when providing our services to you’** , you can ask us to provide you with a copy of that information in a structured data file. 

* * *

You can ask us to send your personal information directly to another service provider, and we will do so if this is technically possible. We will not provide you with a copy of your personal information if it contains the personal information of other individuals or we have another lawful reason to withhold that information.

* * *

 **Automated decision making, including profiling**

 **How to contact us:**

Any data subject request can be made in writing to: 

UK Legal & Compliance Department  
Thomas Cook Airlines Limited,    
Hangar 1   
Western Maintenance Area,  
Runger Lane,   
Manchester Airport,   
Manchester,   
M90 5FL 

Alternatively you can make a data subject request by e-mail to:  

Once you have made your request and provided us with the information we need to begin a search for the data we hold on you (including proof of your identity), we will have 30 days to respond.

 **Making a complaint  **

We encourage you to contact us if you have a complaint and we will seek to resolve any issues or concerns you may have.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with the data protection regulator where you believe your legal rights have been infringed, or where you have reason to believe your personal information is being or has been used in a way that doesn’t comply with the law.  

The contact details for the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the data protection regulator in the UK, are available on the ICO website.

If you wish to contact us about this Privacy Policy, you can e-mail or write to the Thomas Cook Group Data Protection Officer or the Thomas Cook Group Airlines Data Protection Officer using the contact details above.

Alternatively, you can contact our Group Data Protection Officer using the following details:

Thomas Cook Group plc  
3rd floor, south building  
200 Aldersgate  
London  
EC1A 4HD  
United Kingdom

Email: [groupDPO@thomascook.com](mailto:groupDPO@thomascook.com)  
Phone: +44(0) 207 557 6400[  
](mailto:groupDPO@thomascook.com)

 **If you want to find out more about our data retention policy, please read more here.**

Where you’ve made a booking or other purchase with us, your personal information will be retained to ensure we provide the best possible customer service to you.  We retain your personal data for as long as is necessary for us to use your data as set out in this Privacy Policy.  

This will generally be for up to 7 years in relation to bookings/purchases, or 2 years since you last engaged with us after receiving a marketing communication, or such other time that may be required for our legal and audit purposes or that is required by law.  

 **We take data security very seriously, to find out our approach to this please read more here.**

The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure, and although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Sites, therefore any transmission is at your own risk.

Once we have received your information, we will take all reasonable steps to keep your personal data secure and to try to prevent any unauthorised access, use or loss of your data, by putting in place appropriate security measures and limiting access to those who have a business need to know.  

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers.  Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Sites, you are responsible for keeping that password confidential.  We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

We have a process to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and the ICO of a breach where legally required to do so.

 **Our Sites include links to other websites which include privacy policies of their own.   To learn more about this, please read here.**

Our Sites contains links to and frames of websites of our principals, suppliers, advertisers and other third parties. You can tell when a third party is involved in supplying a product or service you have requested because their name will appear with ours. 

If you follow a link or otherwise use any of these other websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies or for these third party websites. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

 **This site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users. You can find out more about what cookies are at:[www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). The cookies used on our Sites fall into the following categories:**

 **Essential Cookies  
** Some of these cookies are essential to make this site work properly, to allow you to make your travel booking or other purchases, and to enable Thomas Cook Airlines Limited to fulfil your purchase requests

 **Customer Experience Cookies (Analytics, Customisation & Tracking)  
**These other types of cookie help us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our site, allow us to track your experience between different devices to improve our site or the way we provide our service to customers.

 **Advertising Cookies  
** Some cookies, are used to provide you with information or offers from Thomas Cook companies or third parties that we consider will be of interest to you. Web publishers, advertisers and ad networks use cookies and data to optimise advertising effectiveness, and we participate in cookie-based exchanges to make this happen. Our cookie based advertising activity will broadly fall into the following areas:

 **Third party adverts on our Sites and social media  
** This type of advertising is intended to provide you with a selection of products/services that you’ve viewed on other third party websites, or social media channels, which are presented to you by our agency when you visit our Sites or social media channels.

* * *

The adverts may feature variations on the products/services that might be considered relevant to your browsing history on these other third party websites.

 **Thomas Cook adverts on third party websites  
** This type of advertising is intended to provide you with a selection of travel related products/services that you’ve viewed on our website, which are presented to you by our agency when you visit other selected websites or social media channels. The adverts may feature different Thomas Cook products/services that might be considered relevant to your browsing history.

We use advertising solutions delivered by Criteo to serve you these advertisements.  Where we share data for the purposes mentioned above, it is encrypted and does not include your name.

* * *

 **What types of cookies do Thomas Cook Airlines use?**

  *  **Criteo** (hostname .criteo.com)
  *  **Doubleclick** (hostname .doubleclick.net)
  *  **Google Analytics** (hostname .thomascookairlines.com)
  *  **nanoRep** (hostname [my.nanorep.com](http://my.nanorep.com/))
  *  **Qubit** (hostname [tally-1.qubitproducts.com](http://tally-1.qubitproducts.com/))
  *  **SessionCam** (hostname [ws.sessioncam.com](http://ws.sessioncam.com/))
  *  **Google Tag Manager** (hostname .googletagmanager.com)
  *  **Bold Chat** (hostname [livechat.boldchat.com](http://livechat.boldchat.com/))
  *  **Facebook** (hostname .facebook.net; .facebook.com)
  *  **Yieldify** (hostname .yieldify.com)
  *  **Yahoo** (hostname .yimg.com)
  *  **Bing** (hostname .bing.com)
  *  **Affilinet** (hostname .successfultogether.co.uk)

 **Cookies through Criteo:**

  *  **Advertising.com** (hostname .[at.atwola.com](http://at.atwola.com/))
  *  **Clickonometrics** (hostname .clickonometrics.pl)
  *  **Right Media** (hostname [ads.yahoo.com](http://ads.yahoo.com/))
  *  **Smart Adserver** (hostname .smartadserver.com)
  *  **ToneFuse** (hostname .clickfuse.com)
  *  **Underdog Media** (hostname .udmserve.net)
  *  **Xaxis** (hostname .rcsadv.it)

 **How do I change my cookies settings?**  
You can set your browser to reject cookies (see the ‘Help’ menu of your browser to find out how to do this), but please bear in mind that if you do this, certain personalised features of this website cannot be provided to you.

In order to help us maintain and improve our service to you we also use 'cookies' to collect information about your use of the website. Cookies are a feature of web browser software that allows web servers to temporarily store information within your browser, which in turn allows us to recognise the computer used to access our site.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies but you can delete existing cookies from your browser. You can also edit your browser options to choose not to receive cookies in future. We will use cookies to keep track of the transaction from one page to the next. We use third-party application service providers to perform some tracking functions. These companies will use cookie-based information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to measure advertising effectiveness.

We will also collect information about your visit to our website, based on your browsing (click stream) activities. This information will include the pages you browse and products and services viewed or booked for example.

This helps us to better manage and develop our offers and to provide you with better products and services tailored to your individual interests and needs. We will use this information to measure the entry and exit points of visitors to the Site and respective numbers of visitors to various pages and sections of the Site and details of searches performed.

We can also use this information to measure the usage of advertising banners, other click-throughs from the site. We can disclose information of this nature in aggregate form to third parties, personal information on individual visitors will not be passed on to any third party.

 **Declining Cookies**

Please note: 

  * If you choose to remove cookies parts of website you are on may not work properly or your use of the website may be impaired.
  * If  you choose to use this site without declining any non-essential cookies, then your use will constitute implied consent to the non-essential cookies that are set.

 **To enable or disable cookies, follow the instructions below for the browser version you are using.**

 **Microsoft Internet Explorer**

  * Select "Internet Options" from the Tools menu
  * Click on the "Privacy" tab
  * Click the "Default" button (or manually slide the bar down to "Medium") under "Settings"
  * Click "OK"

 **Mozilla Firefox**

  * Go to the "Tools" menu
  * Select "Options"
  * Select the "Privacy" icon
  * Check the box corresponding to "Allow sites to set cookies"
  * Click "OK" to save changes

 **Google Chrome**

  * Select "Preferences" from the Edit menu
  * Find the "Cookies" section in the "Advanced" category
  * To enable: Select "Accept all cookies" (or "Enable all cookies")
  * Click "OK"

 **Safari**

  * Open Safari if it is not already open
  * Choose Safari > Preferences, and then click “Privacy”
  * In the “Block cookies” section, specify whether Safari should accept cookies from websites, and when

We reserve the right to update or alter this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please check this page regularly for changes to this policy. You can request a copy of a previous version of our privacy policy. 

March 2019, version 2
